<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ryan Derr&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ryan Derr&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 10:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Secure Access to Private Cassandra with HashiCorp Boundary</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/posts/boundary-cassandra-hcp-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/posts/boundary-cassandra-hcp-demo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While building a project with a full AWS stack, I needed Cassandra as my database solution. Initially, I looked into AWS Keyspaces (Amazon&amp;rsquo;s managed Cassandra service), but discovered it doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer a way to keep your service endpoints truly private. In lieu of this, I decided to self-host a Cassandra DB instance on a private EC2 instance, allowing me to set my ingress and egress through a private IP. However, this exposed a new challenge: how do you securely access and manage a database that you&amp;rsquo;ve intentionally made unreachable from the internet?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Postgres RDS IAM Authentication</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/posts/aws-psql-rds-iam-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 16:21:27 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/posts/aws-psql-rds-iam-auth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;securely-accessing-aws-postgresql-rds-instances-with-iam&#34;&gt;Securely Accessing AWS PostgreSQL RDS Instances With IAM&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Relational database services have long been a cornerstone for storing and retrieving application data, dating back to the 1970s. However, managing credentials for applications, users, and administrators has always been a challenge due to the static nature of traditional credentials. With AWS RDS, we can address this issue by offering built-in IAM authentication for RDS PostgreSQL, enabling secure, short-lived access scoped to specific users or groups. Additionally, this approach enhances auditing capabilities by allowing detailed tracking of who accessed the database and when.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging AWS Roles for Enhanced Security in GitHub Workflows</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/posts/aws-terraform-github-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 01:53:29 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/posts/aws-terraform-github-auth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;moving-away-from-aws-access-keys&#34;&gt;Moving Away From AWS Access Keys&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a considerable period, I, like many others, relied on Terraform to provision my resources within AWS. Terraform, right out of the box, offers multiple authentication methods to access, provision, modify, or destroy resources, not to mention its support for remote state.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, I opted for the straightforward approach, using &lt;code&gt;AWS_ACCESS_KEY_ID&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;AWS_SECRET_ACCESS_KEY&lt;/code&gt; for a pipeline user to handle the authentication. However, I soon encountered a significant challenge. I wanted to retain exclusive approval rights for changes to AWS via a GitHub environment, while my collaborators needed access to the AWS state to perform plans and ensure the proposed changes would function as expected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 14:41:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My name is James Derr, but I&amp;rsquo;m more commonly known as Ryan. I am a dedicated software engineer with a passion for continuous learning and knowledge sharing. When I&amp;rsquo;m not coding, I enjoy outdoor activities such as bouldering and paddle boarding, and I&amp;rsquo;m also an avid participant in Dungeons and Dragons campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;professional-experience&#34;&gt;Professional Experience&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Software Engineer At HashiCorp&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Software Engineer at General Motors&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Database Administrator at Paycom Payroll&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;technical-skills&#34;&gt;Technical Skills&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;programming-languages&#34;&gt;Programming Languages&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Java&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Go&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;TypeScript&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;cloud-platforms&#34;&gt;Cloud Platforms&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Azure&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;AWS&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;DigitalOcean&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;tools-and-frameworks&#34;&gt;Tools and Frameworks&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spring&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Quarkus&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Apache Camel&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SQL&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kafka&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Git&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;development-lifecycle&#34;&gt;Development Lifecycle&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Docker&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Terraform&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ArgoCD&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Helm&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CI/CD Pipelines&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Wireguard Vpn Via Terraform</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/posts/aws-wireguard-vpn-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 12:30:35 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/posts/aws-wireguard-vpn-terraform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-the-ec2-wireguard-vpn-terraform-module&#34;&gt;Introducing the EC2 WireGuard VPN Terraform Module&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the ever-evolving landscape of the digital age, ensuring secure and efficient communication is paramount. Virtual Private Networks (VPNs) play a crucial role in establishing secure connections, and with the rise of cloud services, creating VPN solutions leveraging the cloud is easier than ever. Today, I am excited to introduce a powerful tool that simplifies the process of setting up a WireGuard VPN on an AWS EC2 instance – my open source &lt;a href=&#34;https://registry.terraform.io/modules/RyanDerr/ec2-wireguard-vpn/aws/latest?tab=inputs&#34;&gt;EC2 WireGuard VPN Terraform Module&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS ECS Faster &amp; Prolonged Shutdown Efficiency</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/posts/aws-ec2-shutdown-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 12:38:29 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/posts/aws-ec2-shutdown-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Containerization has revolutionized the way applications are deployed and managed, providing enhanced scalability and agility. Amazon Elastic Container Service (&lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/ecs/&#34;&gt;ECS&lt;/a&gt;), a highly scalable and fully managed container orchestration service, is at the forefront of this container revolution. In &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2023/06/amazon-ecs-tasks-faster-prolonged-shutdown/&#34;&gt;June 2023&lt;/a&gt;, AWS announced a significant improvement to Amazon ECS, introducing faster and prolonged shutdown capabilities for tasks. This update aims to optimize resource utilization and enhance the overall efficiency of container management.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Pages vs. Vercel: Choosing the Right Platform for Your Website</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/posts/gh-vs-vercel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 12:36:58 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/posts/gh-vs-vercel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the world of web development, choosing the right platform to host your website is crucial. Two popular options are GitHub Pages and Vercel. Both platforms offer powerful features, but they have distinct differences that can impact your decision. In this blog post, we will explore when to use GitHub Pages and Vercel, along with their benefits and drawbacks, helping you make an informed choice for your web hosting needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Case For PoshGit</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/posts/posh-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 12:42:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/posts/posh-git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As developers, our daily workflow often revolves around Git and I&amp;rsquo;m no different. It&amp;rsquo;s the go-to version control system for managing code changes, collaborating with teammates, and ensuring project integrity. While I always lean toward using systems that run Bash (shoutout to Unix), that&amp;rsquo;s not always an option and using Git from the command line can be tedious and time-consuming. Enter &lt;strong&gt;PoshGit&lt;/strong&gt; - a PowerShell module designed to enhance your Git experience and streamline your workflow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
