<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GitHub on Ryan Derr&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://www.ryanderr.dev/tags/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GitHub on Ryan Derr&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 01:53:29 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.ryanderr.dev/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging AWS Roles for Enhanced Security in GitHub Workflows</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanderr.dev/posts/aws-terraform-github-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 01:53:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ryanderr.dev/posts/aws-terraform-github-auth/</guid>
      <description>Moving Away From AWS Access Keys For a considerable period, I, like many others, relied on Terraform to provision my resources within AWS. Terraform, right out of the box, offers multiple authentication methods to access, provision, modify, or destroy resources, not to mention its support for remote state.
In the beginning, I opted for the straightforward approach, using AWS_ACCESS_KEY_ID and AWS_SECRET_ACCESS_KEY for a pipeline user to handle the authentication. However, I soon encountered a significant challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Pages vs. Vercel: Choosing the Right Platform for Your Website</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanderr.dev/posts/gh-vs-vercel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 12:36:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ryanderr.dev/posts/gh-vs-vercel/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the world of web development, choosing the right platform to host your website is crucial. Two popular options are GitHub Pages and Vercel. Both platforms offer powerful features, but they have distinct differences that can impact your decision. In this blog post, we will explore when to use GitHub Pages and Vercel, along with their benefits and drawbacks, helping you make an informed choice for your web hosting needs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
