<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud on Ryan Derr&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/tags/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud on Ryan Derr&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 12:30:35 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AWS Wireguard Vpn Via Terraform</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/posts/aws-wireguard-vpn-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 12:30:35 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/posts/aws-wireguard-vpn-terraform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-the-ec2-wireguard-vpn-terraform-module&#34;&gt;Introducing the EC2 WireGuard VPN Terraform Module&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the ever-evolving landscape of the digital age, ensuring secure and efficient communication is paramount. Virtual Private Networks (VPNs) play a crucial role in establishing secure connections, and with the rise of cloud services, creating VPN solutions leveraging the cloud is easier than ever. Today, I am excited to introduce a powerful tool that simplifies the process of setting up a WireGuard VPN on an AWS EC2 instance – my open source &lt;a href=&#34;https://registry.terraform.io/modules/RyanDerr/ec2-wireguard-vpn/aws/latest?tab=inputs&#34;&gt;EC2 WireGuard VPN Terraform Module&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS ECS Faster &amp; Prolonged Shutdown Efficiency</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/posts/aws-ec2-shutdown-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 12:38:29 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.ryanderr.dev/en/posts/aws-ec2-shutdown-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Containerization has revolutionized the way applications are deployed and managed, providing enhanced scalability and agility. Amazon Elastic Container Service (&lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/ecs/&#34;&gt;ECS&lt;/a&gt;), a highly scalable and fully managed container orchestration service, is at the forefront of this container revolution. In &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2023/06/amazon-ecs-tasks-faster-prolonged-shutdown/&#34;&gt;June 2023&lt;/a&gt;, AWS announced a significant improvement to Amazon ECS, introducing faster and prolonged shutdown capabilities for tasks. This update aims to optimize resource utilization and enhance the overall efficiency of container management.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
