<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AWS on Ryan Derr&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://www.ryanderr.dev/tags/aws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AWS on Ryan Derr&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 01:53:29 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.ryanderr.dev/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging AWS Roles for Enhanced Security in GitHub Workflows</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanderr.dev/posts/aws-terraform-github-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 01:53:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ryanderr.dev/posts/aws-terraform-github-auth/</guid>
      <description>Moving Away From AWS Access Keys For a considerable period, I, like many others, relied on Terraform to provision my resources within AWS. Terraform, right out of the box, offers multiple authentication methods to access, provision, modify, or destroy resources, not to mention its support for remote state.
In the beginning, I opted for the straightforward approach, using AWS_ACCESS_KEY_ID and AWS_SECRET_ACCESS_KEY for a pipeline user to handle the authentication. However, I soon encountered a significant challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Wireguard Vpn Via Terraform</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanderr.dev/posts/aws-wireguard-vpn-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 12:30:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ryanderr.dev/posts/aws-wireguard-vpn-terraform/</guid>
      <description>Introducing the EC2 WireGuard VPN Terraform Module In the ever-evolving landscape of the digital age, ensuring secure and efficient communication is paramount. Virtual Private Networks (VPNs) play a crucial role in establishing secure connections, and with the rise of cloud services, creating VPN solutions leveraging the cloud is easier than ever. Today, I am excited to introduce a powerful tool that simplifies the process of setting up a WireGuard VPN on an AWS EC2 instance – my open source EC2 WireGuard VPN Terraform Module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS ECS Faster &amp; Prolonged Shutdown Efficiency</title>
      <link>http://www.ryanderr.dev/posts/aws-ec2-shutdown-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 12:38:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ryanderr.dev/posts/aws-ec2-shutdown-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Containerization has revolutionized the way applications are deployed and managed, providing enhanced scalability and agility. Amazon Elastic Container Service (ECS), a highly scalable and fully managed container orchestration service, is at the forefront of this container revolution. In June 2023, AWS announced a significant improvement to Amazon ECS, introducing faster and prolonged shutdown capabilities for tasks. This update aims to optimize resource utilization and enhance the overall efficiency of container management.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
